A Guide to the University of Virginia Hospital Professional Staff Files 1951-1990
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
University of Virginia Hospital Professional Staff Files 1951-1990
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
ms-25
Two Hollinger Boxes of processed materials
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
University of Virginia Health System House Staff Office
Biographical/Historical Information
The University of Virginia School of Medicine was established as one of the University's original eight schools when UVa opened in 1824, and in 1901 the University of Virginia Hospital was opened with Dr. Paul Barringer as Superintendent. Since its opening in 1901, the University of Virginia Hospital has expanded its physicians, departments, and Hospital facilities.
The list of the UVa physicians from 1951 to 1990 show general changes that took place in the Hospital through these years, including the increase in the number of physicians, promotion process of the physicians, and specialization of the Hospital departments.
Scope and Content
This Collection is composed of lists of physicians who have been appointed by the University of Virginia Hospital from 1951 to 1990. The list of 1953 is not extant. The Collection contains 39 files in two boxes. Files are arranged by chronological order and names of the physicians are listed by department. Some years have more than one version of the list with handwritten corrections and adding explanation on the materials.
Arrangement
Files are arranged by chronological order.
Contents List
- UVa Hospital - Professional Staff July 1, 1951
- UVa Hospital - Professional Staff July 1, 1952
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1954
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1955
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1956
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1957
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1958
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1959 July 1, 1959
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1960 July 1, 1960
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1961
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1962
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1963
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff July 1, 1964
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1965-1966
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1966-1967
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1967-1968
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1968-1969
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1969-1970
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1970-1971
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1971-1972
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1972-1973
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1973-1974
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1974-1975
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1975-1976
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1976-1977
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1977-1978
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1978-1979
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1979-1980
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1980-1981 1980-1981
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1981-1982
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1982-1983
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1983-1984
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1984-1985
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1985-1986
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1986-1987
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1987-1988
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1988-1989
- UVa Hospital Professional Staff 1989-1990